Luis Souza

Mobile, Web and Application Developer & Designer

Advanced knowledge of Mobile, Web and Application development and programming languages.

Education and experience focused on both sides - tech & business - plus, project management, leadership and design.

Education

2018-09 2020-04 Mobile Application Design & Development

Algonquin College - Ottawa | ON

Magna Cum Laude with Honours | Dean's List (2019/2020)

GPA: 3.91/4.0

2004-01 2006-02 **Business Management**

Anhembi Morumbi University - Sao Paulo | BR

GPA: 8.8/10.0

Certification

2020-03 Design Thinking Practitioner | IBM

Professional Experience

2021-04 Present

Full-Stack Developer

PHD Solutions - Burlington | ON

- Developed React/TypeScript web application with Redux, and an IoT solution with .NET back-end.
- Developed ASP.NET web application with Identity server, SQL server, Azure.
- Developed WPF (Windows Presentation Foundation) application using .NET Framework and Web APIs on AWS (Amazon Web Services) environment.
- Published Web APIs in AWS API Gateway and Windows application in AWS S3 for the application user's access and versioning control for updates.
- Monitored Web APIs access and use with AWS CloudWatch and other AWS tools.
- Supported the application databases in AWS DynamoDB and adapted/improved them whenever needed.

2021-01 2021-03 Web Developer - Style Expert

Coach Association of Canada - Ottawa | ON

- Converted a whole web application developed in ASP.NET to be responsive for mobile and web.
- Reviewed the whole CSS styles of the web application with +18K lines using SASS.
- Organized, normalized and grouped the styles generating +75 major groups.
- Reviewed and applied WCAG 2.0 AA to all possible conditions.

2020-04 2021-12

Software Developer

Fitted - Startup - Ottawa | ON

- Developed the iOS App features with Swift 5, using AR Kit 3 (Augmented Reality), Apple ID, Google and Facebook SDKs, with Apollo, GraphQL and PostgreSQL.
- · Supported the Web application developed in React with GraphQL and PostgreSQL.

🏦 44 Glen Rd Hamilton, ON, L8S 4N2

(613) 618-4878

lhmscanada@gmail.com

appdevcanada.qithub.io

Programming Languages

React	••••
JavaScript	
.NET / C#	
HTML	
CSS	
Xamarin	
.NET MAUI	•••00
DBs (SQL/NoSQ)	•••00

Kotlin ••000 ••000

Java

Swift

Tools

React Native ()

Visual Studio
Visual Studio Code
Adobe Xd/Figma/Sketch
Xcode
Adobe Illustrator/Photoshop
Android Studio
SASS
Git/Github/GitLab
Node.JS
Docker
IntelliJ

•••• ••000 ••000 ••000

••000

00000 00000

••••

•••0

Cordova (€/♠)

Skills

REST APIs	••••
Google APIs	
Project Management	••••
User Interface (UI)	
Object-Oriented Prog.	
User Experience (UX)	
Data Visualization	
WCAG 2.x	
Augmented Reality (ARKit)	
Design Thinking	•••00

Languages

IoT (Internet of Things)

English	
Spanish	•••00
Portuguese	••••

44 Glen Rd Hamilton, ON, L8S 4N2

**** (613) 618-4878



appdevcanada.github.io

2020-06 2020-08

Full-Stack Developer / Research Assistant

Algonquin College | Driven High Performance Lab - Startup - Ottawa | ON

Mobile, Web and Application Developer & Designer

- Designed the framework and Information Architecture from Backend to Frontend, with data analytics and development tools.
- Developed the MERN (Mongo/React/Express/Node) stack solution using NiFi data analytics, Matlab, MongoDB Atlas, React Frontend, Javascript API with libraries Ant Design data visualization, Plotly, Redux, Mailgun and Express, all in IBM Cloud with Docker.

2020-01 2020-04

Team Lead / iOS Developer

Algonquin College | Fitted - Startup - Ottawa | ON

- Planned, managed, arranged and followed up all the main tasks (±100), with a team of 14 resources and stakeholders.
- Built the Augmented Reality feature for the iOS App using Swift with ARKit 3.
- Deployed the project on time and scope with 20 most important requirements.

2019-09 2020-04

Program Assistant

Algonquin College - Ottawa | ON

 Supported around 40 to 60 students of the Programs Mobile App Design & Dev (MADD) and Internet App and Web Dev (IAWD), assisting them to accomplish 5+ assignments each and solving technical issues, bugs and environment-settings, for all the program languages as Javascript, React, React Native, Swift, Kotlin, Xamarin, Java, C++, C#, HTML, and CSS.

2019-05 2019-09

Software Developer / Research Assistant

Algonquin College | HTO - Ottawa | ON

- Developed an IoT (Internet of Things) solution with C++, controlling devices like temperature sensors, BLE (Bluetooth 5), Ethernet and Wi-Fi integration with Web Server and JSON file in a real-time application.
- Figured out a way and a combination of 4 components to bypass hardware/ software issues and deployed the solution working completely.

2018-11 2019-08

Software Developer / Project Assistant

Algonquin College | Makerspace - Ottawa | ON

- Created small apps in Google Sheets using G Suite APIs to manage the 3D printing pool and physical access to the lab, providing better feedback to the users related to taking back the printings.
- Established some Makerspace controls creating safe user guidelines, procedures and KPIs to manage staff and students' projects.

2018-06 2016-01 CEO / Founder

Cloud 3D - Sao Paulo | BR | 3D printing and design company.

2012-06

Lead Web Developer

2015-12

SulAmerica Insurance Co. - Sao Paulo | BR

- Created one in-house web app, using G Suite APIs and third-party SDK, to coordinate 60+ corporate IT projects with dash-boards, allowing the project managers and internal clients to contribute and follow up on their projects and forecasts.
- Designed the appearance, layout and flow of the Web site following the company's guidance and style.
- Developed the main components of the solution and implement coding standards to be followed by the team, with cross-browser compatibility in a graded browser support environment.
- Worked with the Database and Architecture teams to explain the solution, find and solve issues.
- Supported the presentation of the technical proposal for the board members.

2012-05 2007-03

IT Compliance Analyst / IT Compliance Manager Santander Bank - Sao Paulo | BR | Financial institution.

2002-12

Full-Stack Developer / Project Coordinator

2007-02 | SulAmerica Insurance Co. - Sao Paulo | BR

- Coded one Health full-stack app in Visual Basic/MS-SQL using biometrics data to identify 1000+ clients a day.
- Oversaw Medical Web App Services using Java (J2EE, Struts, EJB, JSP and WebSphere), CICS/Cobol, Oracle and DB2 development in a day-by-day operational support team.
- Brought better results to the company and helped increase the annual revenue (intangible) due to better data controls, in a variety of environments, platforms, clients and a diverse support team with 10 resources (skills and experiences).